#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ricky-ailani (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Security Audits
Containerization
Team Management

### Languages

Marathi (Limited Working)
English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Professional Working)
Sindhi (Native or Bilingual)

# Ricky Ailani

Sr. Technical Architect | Ex Morgan Stanley | Cards | Transactional Banking | Wealth Management | Advisory | Discretionary Trading | Enterprise Architecture | Azure | Agile Transformation | Microservices | .NET FullStack

London Area, United Kingdom

# Summary

Seasoned Full stack Senior Software Developer and Team Lead with total 13+ years experience including heading up successful development teams through Agile and careful delegation.

I am a technology enthusiast who thrives to work in challenging environments. Working in current capacity as an Team Lead for building various full stack n-Tier, distributed, parallel and Realtime processing systems based on SOA.

Particularly interested in web based development using Microsoft .Net and Distributed technologies. Well versed with latest technologies like ASP.NET Core, WCF, WebApi, Microservices and distributed technologies like SQL, REDIS, KAFKA.

#### Technical Skills:

Technologies: .NET Core, .NET, WCF, Webapi, ASP .NET, MVC,

Openspan, Pega, SharePoint

Distributed: MS-SQL Server, Zookeeper

Messaging: MQ, KAFKA

Libraries: NUnit, Polly, Dapper, Serilog

Web: Angular, jQuery, TypeScript, AJAX, CSS, HTML5.

Tools: MS Visio, AGGrid, Infragistics, Resharper, Fiddler, Jira,

Teamcity, VSTS, SVN, Stash, NUnit,

# Experience

Investec
Technical Lead
July 2022 - Present (3 years)
London, United Kingdom

Odessa

Senior Technical Architect November 2021 - June 2022 (8 months)

Morgan Stanley 6 years 11 months

Vice President January 2020 - November 2021 (1 year 11 months) Mumbai Area, India

Lead a team of 10+ employees and consultants across four locations for Trading Application used by FA for High Net-worth clients.

This is a fee-based investment advisory Application for clients who prefer to delegate on-going portfolio management decision, via discretionary authority, to Financial Advisor.

Assisting the team to deliver a robust, multi-layered, loosely coupled, full stack Application to perform common Trading operations. Application is built upon modern stack like Dotnetcore, Microservices, Angular, SQL server, Kafka and Solr

# Senior Manager

January 2017 - January 2020 (3 years 1 month)

Started as a senior developer and gradually become a Lead of an RPA team of 8+ Members across multiple locations Designed and developed an Robust, Fault tolerant, reusable and unattended RPA framework to be used across the bots Identifying new process opportunities and accurately analyzing and estimating new processes, quickly assessing feasibility. Identifying and communicating technical requirements, Calculate automation % and FTE benefit and build effort estimates Managed robot's workloads / load balancing using Work Queue

#### Manager

January 2015 - December 2016 (2 years)

Worked in a team of 50+ Employee and consultants to build Enterprise services responsible for delivering solutions for across WM Designed and developed Context switcher service which provides the demographic information of the clients, financial advisors, prospects and external accounts Designed and developed an Intraday Realtime echo system to support intraday updates for any account/prospect/party and groups and show realtime data to user in both FA platform and client platform. Implemented Rest based HATEOS architecture to implement Business view suite of services used across multiple applications in WM to set the context.

## **MphasiS**

Senior Software Engineer

May 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Worked on a Regulatory Portal for a Leading Banking Client

Application provides a facility for business users to upload Policies in a central Place, which will be further shared with FRB

Worked on SharePoint 2013 Object Model, Security features like Session Cloning/Session Hijacking, Prevention of XSS attacks.

Worked on implementing the RDF framework to send the document metadata and relevant Policy document via SFTP to FRB

#### V2 Solutions

Software Engineer

September 2012 - May 2013 (9 months)

Mumbai

Worked as an Developer to create an Application to provide online directory for consumers, consumer's family or caregivers an easier way to access upto-date, comprehensive services offered by national, state, and local social service providers. Client provides integrated health and human services management products that enable organizations to manage growing consumer caseloads with existing resources.

#### Capgemini

Associate Consultant

April 2010 - September 2012 (2 years 6 months)

Worked in the team of 10+ people and developed Application using MVP framework on top of Asp.net and SQL server

Developed a web based Change proposal workflow tool for a Pharmaceutical organization. Certain feature of ECRS includes: Approval process, template creation, Delegation approval etc

# Education

**CHM College** 

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science · (2004 - 2009)

Jaslok High School

 $\cdot$  (2002 - 2004)